<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Camila Ferreira</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Camila Ferreira</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>I never found myself in a Product Management role. But when I discovered it existed, I decided to dive right in this and, nowadays, I’m Product Manager at Resultados Digitais, a Saas company that provides a marketing automation platform for emerging markets.
As many other product managers, I had different experiences until shift to be a product person. I worked first at Tricae, a baby goods e-commerce business, where I learned the online marketing optimization engines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Expectation Ratings: a methodology to quantify the user experience</title>
      <link>/2017/06/12/expectation-ratings-a-methodology-to-quantify-the-user-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/06/12/expectation-ratings-a-methodology-to-quantify-the-user-experience/</guid>
      <description>As part of the day to day challenge of being a Product Manager, the launch of a new product issuper important, especially if we’re going on the right track. Within this context, I would like to share the methodology I used to quantify and validate the user experience when I prototyped the first version of the product I would release after 3 months: the Expectation Rating, created by Albert and Dixon (2003).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How venture capital experience helps me make product decisions</title>
      <link>/2017/03/05/how-venture-capital-experience-helps-me-make-product-decisions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/03/05/how-venture-capital-experience-helps-me-make-product-decisions/</guid>
      <description>The experience as Product Manager has been such an interesting discovery. I never analyse a product without thinking as a venture capitalist. I often look at the growing stages of the company, instead of focusing only on its product functionalities or interfaces.
Before joining Monashees Capital, I worked at Tricae - a Rocket Internet company - with Business Intelligence, and in a second moment with performance marketing. This was my very first time dealing with technology and in a startup as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now I know why there are so few women Product Managers</title>
      <link>/2016/12/30/now-i-know-why-there-are-so-few-women-product-managers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2016 21:49:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/12/30/now-i-know-why-there-are-so-few-women-product-managers/</guid>
      <description>Although I graduated in Chemical Engineering, I shifted to the digital segment. I love what I do as a Product Manager and everything I’ve learned, but it has definitely not been easy.
My first experience on digital was at Tricae, a baby goods e-commerce business. I started as a marketing analyst, and the whole concept was new to me. Performance Marketing was complex, and I had a lot of technical requirements that made me spend hours studying after work.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>